Okay, so I need y'all to educate me on Hawaii and tourism.
How come they want people to stop coming there?
But when things like the Maui fire happen, they want our resources.
They need help.
They need donations from other people.
How would those places be able to thrive without tourism?
I don't understand.
Ain't nobody going to say it, but I will.
I think this is really sad.
This is not a shot nor disrespect intended to you.
But to ask that question means that you have a very colonized mindset.
You think the way of a colonizer.
I'm not from Hawaii, so I'm going to put this in indigenous terms of people that have been
affected by colonization.
The indigenous, in this case, the people of Hawaii, Hawaiian way of life and mindset when
it comes to living, use of land, and money is not the same as Americans.
Now, do you really think that if not for tourism, the people of Hawaii wouldn't be able to survive?
There's lots of places with palm trees and beaches that survive without tourism.
Tourism is the only way America can survive in Hawaii.
Now, if you understand that, then follow the next concept.
Imagine I break into your house.
I take your house and I say, this is now my house and I'm going to make a lot of money
out of your house.
I'm going to build y'all some dog houses around the house because I'm going to need people
to work for me.
That's where y'all going to live.
Now, if you want, you can come in the house and I'll give y'all jobs on this house that
I've stolen from you.
Then y'all can set the move for the tourists to come here.
Y'all got a dope culture.
We're going to pimp that too.
Y'all take this little bit back to your dog houses and then we're going to take all of this.
Now, the next concept.
Who do you think really loves the land?
Even though the land was stolen by America and they're pimping the land and the people
for all it's worth, when disaster strikes, even though the indigenous people are living
in a dog house, they still know that that is their land.
So you're criticizing the people of Hawaii for saying, look, y'all need to do something.
You made all this money here.
Fix it and get the fuck out and take them entitled ass tourists with you.
Only somebody with a colonized mind would fix their mouth to say, when disaster strikes,
y'all Hawaiians and indigenous people now want our money and resources.
That's the money that they stole from the people, my brother.